RICHARD ANTHONY ÁLVAREZ

■ +1 773 469 9726 | @ rawalvarez731@gmail.com | GitHub | # raulduke.com | Chicago, Illinois

Авоит Ме

My journey in computer science started with a book on C programming, a gift from my father when I wanted to build video games. The difficulties of rendering a triangle on the screen for the first time sparked my interest in what can be achieved on computers. My interest in coding and passion for challenge have driven me to captain competetive programming teams and to build 17 unique open-source projects. Academically, my research in large language models (LLMs) has led to two published papers. I actively create experimental short films and music videos, completing over 15 projects so far. I aim to bring a creative perspective and enthusiastic communication skills to IT and engineering teams. Outside of work, I enjoy reading, visiting local theaters, and hiking.

EDUCATION

Kenyon CollegeBachelor of Arts in Film

Aug 2020 - May 2024

Minor in History and Concentration in Integrated Program in Humane Studies

- **Relevant coursework:** Senior Research Seminar, AI for the Humanities, Software Development, Programming Humanity, Data Structures & Program Design, Introduction to Programming
- Extracurriculars: Horn Gallery Videographer, Club Basketball, KSJP

WORK EXPERIENCE

Library and Information Services (LBIS), Kenyon College

Gambier, Ohio

IT Assistant

Sep 2023 - Feb 2024

At Kenyon College, I supported campus-wide technology needs by preparing workstations, moving office tech, and securely erasing and recycling equipment. I restocked printers daily. I conducted classroom checks under the guidance of team members. I streamlined team projects by applying programming skills, in one instance by generating a spreadsheet of course meetings and classroom locations to determine when our techs could perform maintenance.

HSCHKChicago, Illinois

Research Assistant
Aug 2018 - Nov 2019

At the University of Chicago, I worked under Bernard Dickens III on an academic paper proposing strategies to protect against supply-chain attacks and ensure file integrity using advanced checksum technologies. I attended monthly code reviews and contributed 27 commits to the repository. This role taught me professionalism and collaboration in cybersecurity.

PUBLICATIONS

A Retrieval-Augmented Film Recommendation System | GitHub | Digital Kenyon | May 2024

- Utilized LangChain's OpenAI integration for dynamic query generation based on user preferences, demonstrating the potential for advanced AI and machine learning techniques in digital entertainment.
- Developed a Retrieval-Augmented Film Recommendation System using Node.js, integrating OMDb and TMDb APIs to enhance movie metadata for precise and personalized recommendations.

Unsupervised Deep Learning and PySceneDetect Analysis | GitHub | Digital Kenyon | May 2023

- Analyzed short-format video editing trends using PySceneDetect and DNNs.
- Employed t-SNE and PCA for data visualization and pattern discovery.

Skills

Languages: English (Native), Spanish (Intermediate)

Programming: C, C++, Python, JavaScript/Node, Rust, SQL, MySQL, PHP

Technologies: Docker, DNNs (Deep Neural Networks), NLP (Sentiment Analysis, Topic Modeling), OpenCV, Linux

Frameworks Next.js, React, Tailwind, Scikit-Learn, Keras **Applications**: Davinci Resolve, Adobe Suite, Cinema4D